J.D. Fillmore

Portfolio: https://jdfill.me | E: jd@jdfill.me | Github: https://github.com/jd-fillmore LI: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jd-fillmore/

SUMMARY

Seasoned remote front-end developer with a core focus on driving business results. Experienced in developing websites and web applications that deliver on impact, functionality and accessibility. Employed at one of Canada's largest equipment rental operations.

SKILLS

React, React Hooks, TypeScript, Styled Components, JavaScript (ES5/6), Storybook, GraphQL, Consuming REST APIs (JSON, Fetch API, Axios), GatsbyJS, NextJS, JAMStack, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Flexbox, Bootstrap, Bulma, Netlify, Git (Github), Adobe XD, Adobe Photoshop, Sketch, InVision, Google Analytics, SEO, WCAG / AODA AA Accessibility, Agile / Scrum, Continuous Deployment

EXPERIENCE

Front-End Developer, Team Lead

Dec. 2019 - Present

Battlefield Equipment Rentals (Toromont Cat) | Remote

- Develop national product landing pages, notably generating \$3,000,000 in revenue in May 2020 during the COVID-19 pandemic
- Co-developed, launched and continue to improve bilingual React & TypeScript web application increasing speed, user experience, performance generating over \$1,000,000 of revenue in selling used equipment within the first month
- Focus on improving current legacy websites speed, performance, SEO and WCAG AODA AA Accessibility

Front-End Developer (Contract)

June 2019 - Dec. 2019

VelocityEHS | Remote

- Helped develop front-end for web application used by over 14 million people world-wide, using React, JavaScript, Flexbox, InVision, Sass & Git, utilizing Agile and Scrum methodologies
- Team lead for 2 front end developers and 2 UX designers for WCAG AODA AA Accessibility integration
- Developed Storybook reusable code component library, decreasing development time by over 50%

Front-End Developer, UI / UX Designer, SEO

April 2013 - Present

Freelance & Side Projects | Remote

- Design and develop both client and side project websites and web apps using Adobe XD, Photoshop, Sass, Flexbox, Bootstrap, React, React Hooks, Styled Components, JavaScript (ES5/6), REST APIs (JSON, Fetch API, Axios), GatsbyJS, Netlify and Git (Github)
- Clients 60% increase in all clients overall SEO rankings due to accessibility, speed and performance of websites developed
- Side projects experimenting with API-based and CRUD projects with React, JavaScript

Front-End Developer April 2018 - June 2019

Thrillworks | Burlington, ON

- Developed AODA AA accessible websites for some of Canada's biggest brands, including Tim Hortons and PC Financial using React (GatsbyJS), JavaScript, Flexbox, Bootstrap & Sass. One of the leading members of the AODA AA Accessibility Board.
- Developed Storybook reusable code component library, decreasing development time by over 60%

Front-End Developer, UI / UX Designer

Sept. 2016 - April 2018

Virtual Image | Hamilton, ON

- Designed and developed websites using Adobe XD, Photoshop, HTML5, CSS3, Flexbox, Bootstrap, Sass & JavaScript
- 60% decrease in development time of websites due to component based libraries

Front-End Developer (Contract)

March 2016 - Sept. 2016

Elite Digital | Toronto, ON

- Designed and developed websites using Adobe XD, Photoshop, HTML5, CSS3, Flexbox, Bootstrap, Sass & JavaScript
- 5 websites designed, developed and launched within the first week of employment

EDUCATION

Durham College, Oshawa, ON | Advanced Diploma in Multimedia Design

April 2010

INTERESTS

Hockey, music (guitar player & singer), archery, childcare, mentorship, gaming.